好了！家务做完了
All right! Chores are done.
现在能去玩沙丘赛车吗？
Now can we do some dune bashing?
我没想好 神子
I don't know, Miko.
上次我花了一个星期去清理发声器里的沙子
Last time I spent a week picking sand out of my articulators.
不过市里有个大脚车拉力赛…
But there is a monster truck rally in town...
擎天柱 我收到一个来自秘密波段的信号
Optimus, I'm receiving a signal of our restricted band.
好像来自一艘宇宙飞船 就在这个太阳系内
It appears to be coming from a starship inside the solar system.
是一个汽车人的标识信号
It's an Autobot identification beacon.
还有其他的汽车人吗？
So there are other bots out there?
塞博特恩陷入死寂的时候 很多人都流落到太空
The masses scattered to the galaxies when Cybertron finally went dark.
不过 虎子们经常用假信号当作诱饵
But, cons have been known to bait traps with false beacons.
不明飞船 这是汽车人前哨基地欧米加1号
Unknown vessel, this is Autobot outpost Omega One.
表明你的身份
Identify yourself.
霸天虎作战部队的欢迎仪式 可比这热闹多了
I've had warmer welcomes from Decepticon combat brigades.
千斤顶？
Wheeljack?
你这打虎子老手！
You old Con-crusher!
你大老远跑这儿来干嘛？
What do you do all the way out here?
隔板？是你！
Bulkhead? That's you!
怎么那么多的安全措施？
What's with all the security?
我们住的这块大石头上爬满了虎子们
The rock we are on is crawling with Cons.
你什么时候过来？我们正缺人手
How soon can you get here and even the odds?
明天的某个时刻 但我得踩踩油门
Sometime tomorrow, but put metal to the pedal.
又来了个汽车人？
Another bot's coming here?
这可太酷了！
How cool is that?
千斤顶…
Wheeljack
我只听说过他的大名
I know of him by reputation only.
你确认是他的声纹吗？
Can you verify his voiceprint?
百分之一千是他 擎天柱
He is one thousand percent the real deal, Optimus.
我们会提供着陆坐标 千斤顶
We will send landing coordinate, Wheeljack.
祝旅途平安
Safe journey.
到时候见 哥们儿
See you soon buddy.
我给你准备个隆重的欢迎仪式
I'll make sure you get a proper welcome.
你这朋友什么来头？
So who is the boyfriend?
我和老千是老相识了
Haha, me and Jackie go way back.
我们曾经并肩战斗在…
We were part of the same war unit C
雷霆救援队
C the Wreckers
虎子们碰上我们 只能有来无回！
which means the cons are gonna wish he never found us.
“千斤顶？你大老远跑这儿来干嘛？”
"Wheeljack? What do you do all the way out here?"
“隔板？是你！”
"Bulkhead? That's you."
“怎么那么多的安全措施？”
"What's with all the security."
“我们住的这块大石头上爬满了虎子们”
"The rock we are on is crawling with Cons."
来了个战斗英雄 嗯？
A war hero, mh?
我们要抓紧时间
We haven't much time.
千面客！
Makeshift!
“住的这块大石头上爬满了虎子们”
"The rock we are on is crawling with Cons."
“你什么时候过来？我们正缺人手”
"How soon can you get here and even the odds?"
“明天的某个时刻 但我得踩踩油门”
"Sometime tomorrow, but put metal to the pedal."
“到时候见 哥们”
"See you soon buddy."
“我给你准备个隆重的欢迎仪式”
"I'll make sure you get a proper welcome."
我也会准备一个隆重的欢迎仪式
I do know how to prepare and proper welcome.
千斤顶的飞船正接近着陆区
Wheeljack ship is approaching the landing zone.
他只是碰巧路过吗？
You think he’s here to visit?
说不定会留下来呢！
Maybe he'll stay!
嗯 但得给他找个人类同伴
Hmm, have to find his own human though.
环陆桥开始运行
Ground Bridge cycling up.
都怪该死的吸屑虫！
Uh, blast to the Scrapblets.
自从上次被侵蚀后 设备便大不如前了
The equipment hasn't been the same since the infestation.
就是说 千斤顶将在地球的另一面着陆
So Wheeljack is gonna land half way around the world
然后你再把他接过来？
and then you'll bridge him here?
我们基地的位置要保密 不能冒险
We can't risk revealing the location of our base
这是为防止霸天虎跟踪千斤顶的飞船
just in case the Decepticons are tracking Wheeljack's ship.
哥们 我从没见过你这么兴奋
Dude, I've never seen you so stoked.
噢 你会喜欢上千斤顶的
Ho, you're gonna love Wheeljack.
我们亲如手足！
We were like brothers!
今晚我们要好好乐乐！
And tonight, we are gonna party!
好棒啊！
S-weet!
麻烦来了
Bogies
正向千斤顶的方位迅速接近
closing fast on Wheeljack's position.
这群虎崽子！
Con-scum!
如果你们想扫我的雅兴
If you are trying to ruin my day
可得加把劲了
you are gonna have to try harder.
一群温顺的小猫
You Cons have gone soft on me.
快点 要赶在汽车人到达之前！
Swiftly, before the Autobots arrive!
把桥打开 救护车 我们要错过好戏了！
Open the bridge, Ratchet. We're missing all the action.
我去准备医疗舱
I’ll prepare sig-bay.
给谁准备？虎子们？
Hehe, who for? The Cons?
他可是响当当的千斤顶啊
This is Wheeljack we are talking about.
我没说错吧
Hehe, I told about it.
以为我会需要增援吗？
Ever think I might need a hand here?
啥？去糟蹋一场好戏？
What? And spoil the show?
你漏了一个
You missed one.
如果你们就这么几个人
If this is all you get
这星球的情况可比我想像得要糟
the planet is in bigger trouble than I thought.
老千！
Jackie! Hahahahaha...
有完没完啊 你个流星锤？
Haha, watch the finish, you old racking ball.
老千 过来
Jacky, come here.
这是我另一个死党 神子！
Meet my other best buddy, Miko!
她的实力跟咱俩不相上下
She can wreck with a best of us.
你好
Hi ya.
你好好看着隔板 别让他找麻烦
You keeping Bulkhead out of trouble?
我会的
I try.
但麻烦总是主动找上门来
But trouble finds us anyway.
我们会相处融洽的
We are gonna get along just fine.
擎天柱
Optimus Prime.
久仰大名
It's a privilege.
彼此彼此 战士
Likewise, soldier.
你远道而来 有什么发现？
What have you to report from you long journey?
从一个星球到另一个星球
Been bouncing from rock to rock
寻找朋友和敌人而已
searching for signs of friend or foe.
现在 两样都找到了
Now, I find both.
我们人少 但都是精锐
We are few, but strong.
我们失去过同伴
We have suffered losses
但也得到了教训
but we have grown.
我们也非常欢迎新成员的加入
And we would relish welcome in a new member into our fold.
我感到荣幸
I would be honored.
那就开始狂欢吧！
Then let's get this party started!
真是乐疯了
Oh, joy!
千面客穿过环陆桥的那一刻
The moment Makeshift passed through that Ground Bridge
我们就失去了他的追踪信号
we lost his tracking signal.
汽车人基地看来的确守卫森严
The Autobot base is no doubt heavily shielded to
我们难以摸清它的位置
prevent us from locating it.
不过 没关系
No matter
我对千面客有绝对的信心
I have complete faith in Makeshift.
我们的卧底已经打入了他们内部
Our inside man is already inside.
告诉威震天 如果他觉得隔板认不出那个冒牌货
Tell Megatron he's fragged in the head if he thinks
那他的脑子就有问题了
Bulkhead won't sniff out an impositor.
你还不知道吗 霸天虎现在由我统领
Haven't you heard, I lead the Decepticons now.
你？哈！
You? Hah!
是的 他可能还有利用价值
Yes! Yes... He may yet be of use.
千面客很擅于伪装
Makeshift is very good at keeping up appearances.
他只需骗过你的朋友们
He need only fool your friends long enough
然后从内部打开环陆桥
to open their Ground Bridge from within.
那样我就能知道汽车人基地的位置了
So that I may finally learn the location of the Autobot base.
接着 我派出的突击队
And send in my strike team to
会让擎天柱体内的能量洒遍整个基地
stain its floor with the spilled energon of Optimus Prime.
来吧 老千 让我看看你的能耐！
Come on, Jackie. Show me what you get.
好球！
Oh, oh, hahaha, nice lob.
那是什么？
So, what's that about?
那叫抛球
It’s called Lobby
塞博特恩上最受欢迎的消遣项目
the favorite past time on Cybertron
特别是对于勇士阶级
especially among warrior class.
来吧 拉夫! 让我们看看你的舞姿
Come on, Raf! Show us some moves.
哦 那好吧
Oh, alright.
没错 机器舞
Hehe, of course, they're robot.
擎天柱呢？
Where is Optimus?
兜风去了
Went for a drive.
领袖们不参加派对的
Primes don't party.
冲你来了！
Coming at you! Yew!
你们知不知道 我正在进行精确的校准工作！
You know what? I am attempting to perform sensitive calibrations here!
抱歉 大夫
Sorry, doc.
看来我们有点兴奋过头了
Guess we are a little charged up.
整座桥都是你建的 对吧？
You built this bridge from scratch, huh?
是的
I did.
这的确是个庞大的工程
That’s quite a feat of engineering.
是的 没错
Yes it is.
出问题了吗？
Something wrong with it?
上次运作时的响声听起来不对劲
I didn't care for the way it sounded of this last jump.
我把它关掉了
I put it in shutdown.
那需要用的时候怎么办？
What if you need to use it?
喔 中断磁盘整理程序会造成不可修复的损坏
Woo... I can't disrupt the defrag process without causing unreparable damage.
那…磁盘整理程序需要多久？
So uh... How long would the defrag take?
如果幸运的话 几小时吧
A few hours, if we are lucky.
也可能更久
Maybe longer.
千面客还没有打开他们的环陆桥
Makeshift still hasn't open their Ground Bridge
或传送他们的坐标
or otherwise transmitted their coordinates.
尽管他伪装得天衣无缝
His disguise may be flawless
但他不可能把汽车人一骗到底！
but he won't fool the Autobots forever!
当时我们在那里 通讯失灵
So there we were, no communications
能量不足 被虎子们包围
low on energon, surrounded by Cons.
猜猜千斤顶是怎么干的？
So what does wheeljack do?
告诉他们 老千！
Hehe, tell them, Jackie.
当然是我最拿手的！
Well, what I do best.
他拧开唯一的一颗手雷塞进了主换热器
He chucked his only grenade and smacked into the primary heat exchanger.
是啊 当时看来这主意不错
Yea, seem like a good idea at that time.
整个区域像超新星爆发一样
The joint went supernova!
帅啊…
Awesome...
是啊 现在都还能从我背上找出弹片呢
Yea, I'm still picking shrapnel out of my back side.
我不觉得惊讶
I'm not surprised
就冲你那背部的体积
given the size of your back side.
于是乎 老千有了个外号
There is it, Jackie signature.
“一颗手雷闯天下”
One grenade, one shot.
嘿 你没事吧？
Hey, you are alright?
怎么？
What?
你好像有些反常啊
You don't seem like yourself.
你这话什么意思？
What do you mean?
我不清楚 你似乎过于沉默了！
I dunno you seem, quiet.
在罐子里呆得太久了
Ah, I've been stuck in a can too long.
在我疯掉之前 出去透透气吧
I should go top side before I get stern crazy.
我早上有巡逻任务 你可以一起来
I have patrol in the morning. You can come with.
我们现在就去吧！
Let's go now.
让派对不欢而散？
And break up the party?
拜托 他们多喜欢你啊！
Come on. The gang's loving you.
去讲讲在暗峰山的战斗
You got to tell about the Battle of Dark Mount Pass.
你去吧 讲故事你在行
You'll tell them. You're better at it.
不如让神子带我逛逛你们的基地吧
How about if Miko here shows me the rest of your base.
啊 当然可以 老千 去吧
Well, yea. Sure, Jackie. Go ahead.
参观现在开始
Tour starts now.
你懂乐器吗？
Do you play any instruments?
你能飞吗？你揍过的霸天虎比隔板还多吗？
Can you fly? Have you thrust  more Decepticons than Bulkhead?
你没事吧？
You alright?
没事 只是…有点走神罢了
Yea. Just, out of thoughts I guess.
别告诉我 你…妒忌
Don't tell me you're... jealous.
妒忌神子交到新朋友？怎么会呢
That Miko's making a new friend? Come on.
只是…
Something
只是感觉千斤顶有些不对劲
something is just not right about Wheeljack.
隔板 想想看
Bulkhead, really.
他走过那么多星系
He's travelled galaxies.
你们几个世纪没见了
You haven't ever seen him for centuries.
他可能有点太空时差
He could just be rocket lagged.
你也知道 汽车人也是会变的
Well, bots do change, you know?
老千不会的
Not Jackie.
你哪儿也走不了 汽车人
You are not going anywhere, Autobot.
废话真多
Blablabla...
基本上就是这些
So that's pretty much it.
能量堆 发电机 军械库
Energon stock pile, power generator, armory
都是可以用来玩大爆炸的
everything you need to blow the joint sky high.
这个堡垒具体在哪里？
Where is this bunker located, exactly?
如果我告诉了你
If I told you
我就得把你的火种室扯出来！
I'd have to rip out your spark chamber.
开玩笑的！
Kidding!
就在内华达州的贾斯帕市郊区
Just outside Jasper in Nevada.
虽然我不觉得对你有什么用处
Though I don't expect that'll mean much to you.
说不定有用…
Can't say it does.
那 除了过桥 还有其他出路吗？
So, eh, anyway out of here besides bridging?
问这干嘛？
Why?
你不会是打算要走吧？
You’re not planning to leave already, are you?
来吧 我带你过去
Come on, I'll show you.
差不多了
Almost there.
听着 我比任何人都了解千斤顶
Look, I know Wheeljack better than anyone.
你们在聊什么呢？
Hey, what are you guys talking about?
我刚才在跟他们讲我们在暗峰山的战斗
I was just telling the guys all about you and me, at the Battle of Dark Mount Pass.
那故事可精彩了！
That’s a heck of the story.
没错 讲来听听！
Yep. Tell it.
讲 讲 讲 等我们兜完风后再讲吧？
Talk, talk, talk. How about after we go off roading?
神子 这不关你的事！
Miko, stay out of this.
隔板 别这样
Bulkhead, easy.
我看没必要…
I'm not sure I...
讲！
Tell it!
好吧 既然你要重温过去 隔板
Fine. You want to live in the past, Bulkhead.
雷霆救援队困在了一队霸天虎巡逻队和熔炼坑之间
The Wreckers were trapped between an Decepticon patrol and the melting pit.
虎子们凶猛无比
The cons were vicious
我们被完全压制了
bearing down on us with everything they had.
我和隔板与敌军一番大战
Me and Bulkhead engaged the enemy
把他们变成了废渣
left them for scrap
然后我杀出一条血路
then I made us a way out
踩着他们的后备箱 跳过了熔炼坑
using their backsides as stepping stone to cross the melton metal.
不就是这样吗？
Is that how it happened?
没错
Yea
的确就是这样
that's exactly how it happened.
除了一个小细节
Except for one little thing
我并不在场！
I wasn't there.
什么？
What?
我当时已经离开雷霆救援队 追随了擎天柱
I'd already left the Wreckers to join up with Optimus.
只看千斤顶的公开服役记录 你是不会知道的
But you wouldn't know that if all you did was access Wheeljack's public service record.
隔板 那些事跟这有什么…噢！
Bulkhead, what is that have to do with.. Oah...
神子!
Miko!
别过来 否则我把她捏成肉泥！
Stay back. Or I'll squeeze her into pulp.
千斤顶 你在干什么？
Wheeljack, what are you doing?
霸天虎懦夫！
Decepticon coward!
把女孩放了 我才是你的对手！
Let the girl go and face me.
别心急
Don't fret
接下来的仗够你打的
plenty of fighting to come.
到底有没有真的千斤顶？
Is there a real Wheeljack?
当然有
Oh indeed.
我估计红蜘蛛陛下正拿他找乐子呢
And I expect lord Starscream is making sport of him.
你肯定千面客收到你给他的坐标了吗？
Are you certain we are at the coordinates you supplied to makeshift?
那他还磨蹭什么？！
Then what is taking him?
你们的人也许受到了英雄般的欢迎
Maybe they give your boy such a hero's welcome.
他受到感召 所以弃暗投明了
He got the warm and fuzzies and decided to switch sides.
你不觉得你在以寡敌众吗？
Do you not see that you are vastly out-numbered?
他们是观赏我在你身上打洞的最好观众！
I see fellows who might bestly enjoy watching me pumps up dints into you.
干掉他！
Eh, destroy him!
到时候了！
About time!
瞧啊 瞧啊
Well, well.
让派对正式开始吧！
Let's get this party started!
如果是我 就会在那些臭虫进来之前把洞封上
I'd shut that hole before the stinks come through.
立即冲进环陆桥！
Enter the Ground Bridge now!
脏活儿让我来！
Ugly is mine.
哪个是真的千斤顶?
Which one is the real Wheeljack?
哎呀 我分不清了！
Eh, I lost track!
那才是我的老千！
That's my Jackie.
你 按下开关
You, hit the switch.
是时候清理垃圾了
It's time to take out the trash.
全归你了 哥们
All yours, buddy.
你们还在等什么？去啊！
What are you waiting for? Go!
好球！
Nice lob!
告诉我 至少你知道他们基地所在的位置！
Please, tell me that you at least learned the location of their base!
当然 红蜘蛛陛下
Indeed, lord Starscream.
它在一个隐秘的碉堡里 就在靠近…
It is in a hidden bunker, just outside of...
哇！后退！后退！后退！！
Wow! Back, back, back!
噢 不！
Oh no.
千面客 你这蠢货！
Makeshift, you fool!
就像一个不断循环的噩梦
It's like a recurring nightmare.
现在你是领袖卫队的一员了
Now that you're part of Team Prime.
你得选择一个伪装形态
We need to pick out a vehicle mode for you.
我有个建议
I have some ideas.
嗯 关于那个 小隔
Uh, about that, Bulk.
现在我的飞船修理好了
Now that my ship's repaired.
我很感兴趣 对于外面世界的未知力量
I'm itchy to know, what else I might find out there.
什么 你要离开？
Wait, you're leaving?
为什么？
Why?
千斤顶 记住 这里永远是你的港湾
Wheeljack, know that you always have a haven here.
老千从不原地踏步
Jackie never stays.
但他总会回来的
But he always comes back.
这里能坐下两个人 小隔
There's room for two, Bulk.
即使你的背部再大也不成问题
Even with a backside like yours.
谁知道在外面会找到什么呢？
Who knows who we might find out there?
一些老战友？
Some of the old crew?
听起来不错 老千
Heh, sounds like fun, Jackie.
但我已经心有所属
But my ties are here now
跟他们
with them
还有她
with her.
如果我最要好的队友出了什么岔子
If anything happens to my favorite wreker
我绝不会放过你
I'm coming after you.
我会好好关照他的！
I'll take good care of him.
现在 笑一个！
Now, say Cheese!